<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Productivity on Yannis Rizos</title><link>https://yrizos.com/tags/productivity/</link><description>Recent content in Productivity on Yannis Rizos</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 19:39:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yrizos.com/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Slow Productivity</title><link>https://yrizos.com/writing/slow-productivity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 19:39:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yrizos.com/writing/slow-productivity/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Cal Newport’s book &lt;em&gt;Slow Productivity: The Lost Art of Accomplishment Without Burnout&lt;/em&gt; invites readers to rethink how they work. He challenges the relentless pursuit of efficiency and productivity by advocating for a slower, more deliberate approach. Newport encourages doing fewer tasks, working at a natural pace, and prioritising quality. While these ideas resonate, the execution of the book falls flat in several ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="key-themes-of-slow-productivity"&gt;Key Themes of Slow Productivity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newport critiques the “cult of pseudo-productivity,” where busywork and shallow tasks dominate workplaces. He argues this mindset leads to burnout and diminished output quality, particularly in knowledge work. The book draws heavily on historical figures like Jane Austen, Benjamin Franklin, and John McPhee to illustrate how deliberate pacing can lead to meaningful accomplishments.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Where Do You Do Your Best Thinking?</title><link>https://yrizos.com/writing/where-do-you-do-your-best-thinking/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 12:09:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yrizos.com/writing/where-do-you-do-your-best-thinking/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I finished reading Gabrielle Zevin’s &lt;em&gt;Tomorrow, and Tomorrow, and Tomorrow&lt;/em&gt; on a Saturday morning in October. I had been carrying the final chapter on my old Kindle for 2 weeks, finding reasons to delay. The story deserved better than a rushed ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The forest was quiet that morning except for the wind moving through pine branches and the occasional distant shout from where the children were learning below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every other Saturday, my daughter attends environmental consciousness classes at the Hymettus Forest. She learns through play, discovering how to care for nature, herself, and her group. What began as her educational experience has grown into a meaningful ritual for both of us.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>